Craig Rosen and the Static Disruptors D.C. Groove 149
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
Craig Rosen and the Static Disruptors D.C. Groove Collection
1980-2013
DCPL Special Collections - MLK Library
149
3.75 cubic feet; 3 boxes
The Static Disruptors was a go-go band founded in the 1980s by Craig Rosen. The Craig Rosen and the Static Disruptors D.C. Groove Collection documents the band's career and place in the go-go and hardcore punk scenes in Washington D.C. in the 1980s. Included in the collection are vinyl LPs, cassette tapes, DVDs, and audiotapes. Also included are correspondence, photographs, clippings, and other memorabilia.
Biographical / Historical
The Static Disruptors was a go-go band founded in the 1980s by Craig Rosen. Rosen grew up in Bethesda, Maryland and attended Lawrence University in Appleton, Wisconsin. Prior to Static Disruptors, Rosen was involved in the hardcore music scene, playing with groups such as the Rollins Band. While at Lawrence University, Rosen formed the Static Disruptors in 1980. The band relocated to Washington, D.C. shortly after it was founded and settled on creating and playing go-go music. An all-white band until after its first hit song was released, Static Disruptors learned funk and go-go from the band Mass Extinction, a local D.C. band. In 1982, the group produced their hit "D.C. Groove." The band became the first go-go act to perform at the 9:30 Club and the first to play with a rock band at Sidwell Friends school. Rosen mixed hard rock and punk throughout his go-go sets. The group found that their music struggled to find an audience because it was too go-go for one set of fans and too hardcore for the other. The Static Disruptors dissolved after only recording one single. Rosen went on to produce and collaborate with the likes of Doug E. Fresh and the Prophecy Band. Rosen left D.C. to study film at Columbia University. The Static Disruptors reunited in 2003 for a brief concert during a reunion weekend at Lawrence University.
Scope and Contents
The Craig Rosen and the Static Disruptors D.C. Groove Collection documents the band's career and place in the go-go and hardcore punk scenes in Washington D.C. in the 1980s. Included in the collection are vinyl LPs, cassette tapes, DVDs, and audiotapes. Also included are correspondence, photographs, clippings, and other memorabilia.
- Series 1
  - Go Go Newspaper Clippings, 1980-2014 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Go Go News Clippings, 1980-2014 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Static Disruptors, 1981-1983 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Photographs, undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Island Pictures Correspondence, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Good to Go/ Island Pictures Info, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Funk Go Go Articles, 1984-1985 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Event Ads, undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Spin Article, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Its Not For Me: A Guide for Teachers and the Community, undated (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - DC Commission on the Arts Pamphlet, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Daily Insider Memo, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Static Ds - Graduating from Play School, undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - David Bromberg and Earle Kimel, undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Static Disruptors - 8 Piece Band and Show Ad, undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Static Disruptors at the Thirsty Whale, undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Drawing, undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Psyche Dely - Washington's Best Rock Club, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Static Disruptors Funk Wave Dub, undated (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - East of the River Magazines, 2013 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - "Young Musicians Dreams Die in SE Shooting", 1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Stickers, undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Vinyl LPs, undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Cassettes/DVDs/Audio Tapes, undated (Box 3, Folder 1)